stevepavlina.com 2009-06-29

# Privacy Statement

### Short Version

This site keeps all your personal information secret. Your personal information is not shared with anyone else. 

### Long Version

Pavlina LLC has created this privacy statement for StevePavlina.com in order to demonstrate its firm commitment to privacy. The following statement discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for this web site. 

**Information Automatically Logged**  
This site may log your IP address to help diagnose problems with the web server and to administer this web site. This information is primarily used for general traffic tracking and security. 

**Cookies**  
This site uses cookies to track information about its visitors. This information includes the date/time of visits, pages viewed, and products ordered. 

**Order Forms**  
This site provides order forms for you to buy products. When you place an order, this site collects contact information (like your email address), and financial information (like your credit card number). Contact information from the order forms is used only to get in touch with you when necessary. This includes sending you the product(s) you ordered and contacting you if there's a problem with your order. Financial information that is collected is used to bill you for the order. 

**Newsletter**  
This site allows visitors to sign up for a free newsletter by providing an email address. The email address you provide is used only to send you the free newsletter, and you can unsubscribe by clicking a link in any issue of the newsletter. 

**External Links**  
This site contains links to other sites. This site and its owner(s) are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. 

**Public Forums**  
This site may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or newsgroups available to its visitors. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information, so you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

**Security**  
This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under its control. This site provides a secure server for all credit card orders, securely encrypting all personal data with industry-standard methods. This site does not store credit card numbers for processed orders. 

##  Free _Personal Development Insights_ Newsletter 

Sign up for the FREE _Personal Development Insights_ newsletter to **achieve new breakthroughs** in your habits, career, finances, relationships, health, and spiritual development. With **tens of thousands** of active subscribers, _Personal Development Insights_ is one of the **most popular** self-improvement newsletters in the world. 

Newsletters are sent about once a month, just enough to keep you in the loop but not enough to overwhelm you. 

If you enjoy the free information available on this site, you're sure to appreciate the free newsletter as well. Sign up right here: 

**Note:** You can easily unsubscribe at any time with no hassle -- just click the cancellation link at the bottom of any issue. Your email address will be kept confidential and won't be shared. If you use spam-blocker on your email account, be sure to add the email address _pdinewsletter at stevepavlina.com_ to your whitelist, so the newsletter is allowed through. 

Copyright © 2009 by Pavlina LLC, www.StevePavlina.com. All rights reserved.
